

# Alexander Hernandez Reyes

#### Personal Information

MOBILE: +598 99 270 789 SKYPE: live.alxsenen EMAIL: alxsenen@gmail.com

LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alxsenen/

### **SUMMARY**

I am a pasionate tech sysadmin with 10 years of experience, managing systems and services on Linux and Windows, doing fastly troubleshooting, writing steps plan to follow before deploy a solution. I am empathic, proactive, fast learning, serious and responsible.

Eighth month ago, i decided to change my role as Sysadmin to DevOps Engineer, working with many teams, improving my skills, and making best solution for clients, implementing best practices and solutions on cloud providers, also have create automation methods minimazing delays.

No matter what, i will always do my best for the teams and clients.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

| 02/2022–Present | Devops Engineer, Soho, Uruguay   |
|-----------------|--|
|                 | Working with clusters on EKS.  |
|                 | CI/CD automation and integrations with pipelines using tools like Azure Devops.  |
|                 | Deploy infrastructure using Terraform on AWS.  |
| 12/2021-02/2022 | Devops Engineer, Inswitch, Uruguay   |
|                 | Working with clusters on K8s, OKD, EKS and VMware.   |
|                 | CI/CD integrations with pipelines using tools like Jenkins and Gitlab.   |
|                 | Automation deployments to minimize delays for implementations.   |
| 11/2019-12/2021 | SysOps & Cloud Services, SONDA, Uruguay  |
|                 | Deploying servers on AWS, GCP, Azure, VMware, using many systems like CentOS, RedHat, openSUSE, Debian, Ubuntu.                |
|                 | Starting with basic <b>Docker</b> and <b>Kubernetes</b> , deploying services for internal infrastructure and external clients. |
|                 | Deploying and controlling systems integration with Jenkins and Ansible using our own GitLab internal repository.               |
| 05/2018-09/2019 | Sysadmin, IT Support Engineer, Webmaster, ETECSA, Cuba   |
| 11/2019-12/2021 | SysOps & Cloud Services, SONDA, Uruguay  |
|                 | Deploying servers on AWS, GCP, Azure, VMware, using many systems like CentOS, RedHat, openSUSE, Debian, Ubuntu.                |
|                 | Starting with basic <b>Docker</b> and <b>Kubernetes</b> , deploying services for internal infrastructure and external clients. |
|                 | Deploying and controlling systems integration with Jenkins and Ansible using our own GitLab internal repository.               |
| 06/2014-05/2018 | Sysadmin, IT Support Engineer, Webmaster, DATYS, Cuba  |
| 09/2013-09/2014 | Sysadmin, Webmaster, IT Security Support, UCI, Cuba  |
| 09/2010-09/2013 | IT Technical Security, Webmaster, UCI, Cuba  |

#### **EDUCATION**

| 2017 - 2019 | Telecommunications and Electronics Engineering, ISPJAE - Incomplete |
|-------------|---|
| 2017 - 2018 | Linux Services Administrator, DATYS - Complete                      |
| 08/2011     | Linux System Administrator II, UCI - Complete                       |
| 07/2010     | Linux System Administrator I, UCI - Complete                        |
| 2004 - 2008 | Bachelor of Electronic (B.Elect.), PITOH - Complete                 |

## Skills

- 1. VMware, AWS, GCP, Azure 2. CentOS, RedHat, openSUSE, Debian, Ubuntu, Windows Servers
- 3. Jenkins, Gitlab, Ansible, Bash 4. Apache, Nginx, JBoss, Wildfly 5. Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket
- 6. MySQL, PostgreSQL 7. DevOps Jr. Docker, Kubernetes, Pipelines 8. Troubleshooting

## Languages

- English Intermediate
- Spanish Native